[{
	"question": "Which number logically follows these series 4-6-9-6-14-6-.?",
	"answers": ["6", "17", "19", "21"],
	"correct": "17",
	"questionId": "0001"
},
{
	"question": " Which answer expresses the meaning of the specified word best? reassuring",
	"answers": ["Compassionate", "comforting", "explanatory", "meddlesome"],
	"correct": "explanatory",
	"questionId": "0002"
},
{
	"question": " Tom has a new set of golf clubs. Using a club 8, the ball travels an average distance of 100 meters. Using a club 7, the ball travels an average distance of 108 meters. Using a club 6, the ball travels an average distance of 114 meters. How far will the ball go if Tom uses a club 5?",
	"answers": ["122 meters", "120 meters", "118 meters", "116 meters"],
	"correct": "120 meters",
	"questionId": "0003"
},
{
	"question": " Which answer expresses the meaning opposite of that of the specified word best?",
	"answers": ["Tough", "cowardly", "starch", "strong"],
	"correct": "cowardly",
	"questionId": "0004"
},
{
	"question": " Which word(s) can logically replace the question mark? Water is to a pipe as ? is to a wire ",
	"answers": ["Cord", "electricity", "heat", "gas"],
	"correct": "Cord",
	"questionId": "0005"
},


{
	"question": "Which of the meanings is the best fitting for the specified word? reassuring",
	"answers": ["Displeasure", "injustice", "complaint", "futile"],
	"correct": "complaint",
	"questionId": "0006"
},
{
	"question": "Which one of the four is least like the other four?",
	"answers": ["Dog", "Mouse", "Lion", "Snake"],
	"correct": "Snake",
	"questionId": "0007"
},
{
	"question": "Which number should come next in the series? 1 - 1 - 2 - 3 - 5 - 8 ñ 13",
	"answers": ["8", "13", "21", "26"],
	"correct": "21",
	"questionId": "0008"
},
{
	"question": "Which one of the five choices makes the best comparison? PEACH is to HCAEP as 46251 is to: ",
	"answers": ["25641", "26451", "51462", "15264"],
	"correct": "15264",
	"questionId": "0009"
},
{
	"question": "Mary, who is sixteen years old, is four times as old as her brother. How old will Mary be when she is twice as old as her brother?",
	"answers": ["20", "24", "25", "26"],
	"correct": "24",
	"questionId": "00010"
},
{
	"question": "Choose the word most similar to 'Trustworthy':",
	"answers": ["Resolute","Relevant","Insolent","Reliable"],
	"correct": "Reliable",
	"questionId": "0016"
},
{
	"question": "If you rearrange the letters ëLNGEDNAí you have the name of a(n):",
	"answers": ["Animal","Country","State","City"],
	"correct": "Country",
	"questionId": "0017"
},
{
	"question": "Which one of the numbers does not belong in the following series? 1 - 2 - 5 - 10 - 13 - 26 - 29 - 48",
	"answers": ["5","26","29","48"],
	"correct": "48",
	"questionId": "0018"
},
{
	"question": "Ralph likes 25 but not 24; he likes 400 but not 300; he likes 144 but not 145. Which does he like:",
	"answers": ["10","124","200","1600"],
	"correct": "1600",
	"questionId": "0019"
},
{
	"question": "What is the missing number in the sequence shown below? 1 - 8 - 27 - ? - 125 - 216",
	"answers": ["36","46","64","99"],
	"correct": "64",
	"questionId": "0020"
},

{
	"question": "If book is called watch, watch is called bag, bag is called dictionary and dictionary is called window, which is used to carry the books",
	"answers": ["Dictionary","Bag","Book", "Watch"],
	"correct": "Dictionary",
	"questionId": "0021"
},
{
	"question": "If eraser is called box, box is called pencil, pencil is called sharpener and sharpener is called bag. What will a child write with?",
	"answers": ["Eraser","Box","Pencil","Sharpener"],
	"correct": "Sharpener",
	"questionId": "0022"
},
{
	"question": "if HINDU is coded as 61257, and MAN is coded as 924, then INDIRA will be coded as",
	"answers": ["454626","594921","452787","884572"],
	"correct": "452787",
	"questionId": "0023"
},
{
	"question": "If CARPET IS coded as TCEAPR, then the code NATIONAL would be:",
	"answers": ["NLATIONAL","LANOITAN","LNAANTOI","LNOINTAA"],
	"correct": "LNAANTOI",
	"questionId": "0024"
},
{
	"question": "If CAT: DDT Then BIG : ?",
	"answers": ["CLL","CLM","CML","CEP"],
	"correct": "CLL",
	"questionId": "0025"
},
{
	"question": "Mohit and Kunal are good in Hockey and Volleyball. Sachin and Mohit are good in Hockey and Baseball. Gaurav and Kunal are good in Cricket and Volleyball. Sachin, Gaurav and Rohit are good in Football and Baseball. Who is good in Baseball, Cricket, Volleyball and Football?",
	"answers": ["Sachin", "Kunal", "Gaurav", "Mohit"],
	"correct": "Gaurav",
	"questionId": "0026"
},
{
	"question": "ëFaceí Is Related To ëExpressioní In The Same Way As íHandí Is Related To",
	"answers": ["GESTURE", "WORK", "HANDSHAKE", "POINTING"],
	"correct": "GESTURE",
	"questionId": "0027"
},
{
	"question": "Three ducks and two ducklings weigh 32 kg. Four ducks and three ducklings weigh 44 kg. All ducks weigh the same and all ducklings weigh the same. What is the weight of two ducks and one duckling?",
	"answers": ["20 kg", "40 kg", "60 kg", "64 kg"],
	"correct": "20 kg",
	"questionId": "0028"
},
{
	"question": "Look at this series: 664, 332, 340, 170, ____, 89, ... What number should fill the blank?",
	"answers": ["85", "97", "109", "178"],
	"correct": "178",
	"questionId": "0029"
},
{
	"question": "Look at this series: 12, 11, 13, 12, 14, 13, Ö What number should come next?",
	"answers": ["10", "16", "13", "15"],
	"correct": "15",
	"questionId": "0030"
},
{
	"question": "Look at this series: 36, 34, 30, 28, 24, Ö What number should come next?",
	"answers": ["22","26","23","20"],
	"correct": "22",
	"questionId": "0031"
},
{
	"question": "Look at this series: 7, 10, 8, 11, 9, 12, Ö What number should come next?",
	"answers": ["7","12","10","13"],
	"correct": "10",
	"questionId": "0032"
},
{
	"question": "Look at this series: 2, 1, (1/2), (1/4), Ö What number should come next?",
	"answers": ["(1/3)","(1/8)"," (2/8)","(1/16)"],
	"correct": "(1/8)",
	"questionId": "0033"
},
{
	"question": "Look at this series: 80, 10, 70, 15, 60, Ö What number should come next?",
	"answers": ["20","25","30","50"],
	"correct": "20",
	"questionId": "0034"
},
{
	"question": "Which word does NOT belong with the others?",
	"answers": ["index","glossary","chapter","book"],
	"correct": "book",
	"questionId": "0035"
},
{
	"question": "Which word is the odd man out?",
	"answers": ["trivial","unimportant","important","insignificant"],
	"correct": "important",
	"questionId": "0036"
},
{
	"question": "Which word does NOT belong with the others",
	"answers": ["wing","fin","beak","rudder"],
	"correct": "beak",
	"questionId": "0037"
},
{
	"question": "Which word is the odd man out?",
	"answers": ["hate","fondness","liking","attachment"],
	"correct": "hate",
	"questionId": "0038"
},
{
	"question": "Pick the odd man out?",
	"answers": ["just","fair","equitable","biased"],
	"correct": "biased",
	"questionId": "0039"
},
{
	"question": "As CUP : LIP, so BIRD : ?",
	"answers": ["GRASS","FOREST","BEAK","BUSH"],
	"correct": "BEAK",
	"questionId": "0040"
},
{
	"question": "As Paw : Cat, so Hoof : ?",
	"answers": ["Lamb","Horse","Elephant","Tiger"],
	"correct": "Horse",
	"questionId": "0041"
},
{
	"question": "As Safe : Secure, so Protect : ?",
	"answers": ["Lock","Guard","Sure","Conserve"],
	"correct": "Guard",
	"questionId": "0042"
},
{
	"question": "As Melt : Liquid, so Freeze : ?",
	"answers": ["Ice","Solid","Condense","Push"],
	"correct": "Solid",
	"questionId": "0043"
},
{
	"question": "As Parts : Strap, so Wolf : ?",
	"answers": ["Flow","Animal","Wood","Fox"],
	"correct": "Flow",
	"questionId": "0044"
},
{
	"question": "If white is called blue. blue is called red, red is called yellow, yellow is called green, green is called black, black is called violet and violet is called orange, what would be the colour of human blood?",
	"answers": ["Red","Green","Yellow","Violet","Orange"],
	"correct": "Yellow",
	"questionId": "0045"
},
{
	"question": "If room is called bed, bed is called window, window is called flower and flower is called cooler, on what would a man sleep?",
	"answers": ["Window","Bed","Flower","Cooler","None of these"],
	"correct": "Window",
	"questionId": "0046"
},
{
	"question": "If orange is called butter, butter is called soap, soap is called ink, ink is called honey and honey is called orange, which of the following is used for washing clothes?",
	"answers": ["Honey","Butter","Orange","Soap","Ink"],
	"correct": "Ink",
	"questionId": "0047"
},
{
	"question": "If sand is called air, air is called plateau, plateau is called well, well is called island and island is called sky, then from where will a woman draw water?",
	"answers": ["Well","Island","Sky","Air","None of these"],
	"correct": "Island",
	"questionId": "0048"
},
{
	"question": "If bangle is called cassette, cassette is called tablet table is called game and game is called cupboard, then which is played in the tape recorder?",
	"answers": ["Bangle","Cassette","Table","Cupboard","None of these"],
	"correct": "Table",
	"questionId": "0049"
},
{
	"question": "If green means red, red means yellow, yellow means blue, blue means orange and orange means green, what is the colour of the clear sky?",
	"answers": ["Blue"," Red","Yellow","Green","Orange"],
	"correct": "Yellow",
	"questionId": "0050"
},
{
	"question": "If cloud is called white, white is called rain, rain is called green, green is called air, air is called blue and blue is called water, where will the birds fly?",
	"answers": ["Air","Cloud","White","Rain","Blue"],
	"correct": "Blue",
	"questionId": "0051"
},
{
	"question": "If book is called watch, watch is called bag, bag is called dictionary and dictionary is called window, which is used to carry the books?",
	"answers": ["Dictionary","Bag","Book","Watch","None of these"],
	"correct": "Dictionary",
	"questionId": "0052"
},
{
	"question": "If the animals which can walk are called swimmers, animals who crawl are called flying, those living in water are called snakes and those which fly in the sky are called hunters. then what will a lizard be called ?",
	"answers": ["Swimmers","Snakes","Flying","Hunters","None of these"],
	"correct": "Flying",
	"questionId": "0053"
},
{
	"question": "If water is called food, food is called tree, free is called sky, sky is called wall, on which of the following grows a fruit?",
	"answers": ["Water","Food","Sky","Tree","Wall"],
	"correct": "Sky",
	"questionId": "0054"
}
]